# **TRAVISBURCH**

#### FRONT-END **DEVELOPMENT**

**EMAIL** travisb.burch@gmail.com **PHONE** 704.692.1484 **GIT** github.com/tburch5387

I'm a front-end developer and web designer making a transition in my career after 10+ years in customer facing roles in the tourism industry. My experiences have helped me develop an ability to read between the lines and understand what the client is actually looking for, even when they might not know the right question to ask. I'm a believer in the power of details and know that the little things make big differences.

#### **SKILLSET**

#### **EDUCATION**

HTML CSS

JAVASCRIPT - NOVICE

PHOTOSHOP ILLUSTRATOR

WORDPRESS ADMIN

MAC OS WINDOWS GITHUB MAILCHIMP

JAVA - BASIC UNDERSTANDING SQL - BASIC UNDERSTANDING

CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGEMENT

FURMAN UNIVERSITY (2009)

Bachelor of Arts

DREXEL UNIVERSITY (2011)

Digital Media and Design Coursework

GARDNER-WEBB UNIVERSITY (2015)

MBA - Hospitality and Tourism

TECH TALENT SOUTH (2018/2019)

Code Immersion (HTML/CSS/SQL/Java)

Front End Development (HTML/CSS/Javascript)

**UDEMY** 

Complete Web Designer

**WES BOS** 

Beginner Javascript

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### US NATIONAL WHITEWATER CENTER

#### **Race Director** (2019-2020)

- Plan, organize and execute all aspects of competitive events, including trail and bike races, climbing competitions and paddling events
- Manage a team of volunteers and staff to execute events at a high level and exceed customer expectations
- Code HTML emails in Mailchimp as needed for event notifications
- Design and build online order forms through Formsite

#### Software Support (2019-2020)

- Support primary sales point software (Siriusware) through troubleshooting and liaising with IT and Siriusware Technical support
- Worked with a new ecommerce vendor to set up an integration with Siriusware

## Guest Services Director (2015-2018)

- Manage and facilitate training of a team of up to 50 seasonal, hourly staff
- Oversee and manage all day to day operations of the Guest Services
   Department
- Address and resolve conflicts as they arise, seeking to find a mutually beneficial solution
- Maintain web page via Wordpress CMS

#### GARDNER-WEBB UNIVERSITY/SODEXO

#### Catering Manager (2014-2015)

Manage, plan and oversee execution of all catering for campus events.

# Retail Manager (2013)

- Oversee a staff of 25+ in a fast-paced food service environment across four concepts.
- Create and advertise specials and promotions for all concepts, including design, marketing and execution.

## **Event Coordinator** (2012)

Schedule and organize event calendar and provide on-site management for events

# MOUNTAIN SKY GUEST RANCH

Guest Services Specialist and Hiking Guide (2010-2011)